Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nguyen-tuyet-ngan-bling-70077146 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Graphics
Illustrator
Art Direction

Nguyen Tuyet Ngan (Bling)

UI/UX lead at Zalo

Vietnam

Summary

I am a designer that always questions about the link between the visuals and the mind.

I strive to balance form and function, business goals and user needs. My expertise is building SaaS products, I help making more than 15 MVP for startups in different industries.

Want to see more of my work? Visit https://dribbble.com/ BlingDeneige or https://www.behance.net/bling

Please contact me at: blingdeneige@gmail.com

Experience

PI.EXCHANGE

Lead UI/UX Designer

January 2023 - Present (2 years 3 months)

Operate as part of the product team to design a no-code machine learning tool with data analysis and data preparation and predictive modeling features.

Users could quickly use our pre-built solutions to solve their use cases, for ex: Customer churn prediction, Demand forecasting etc. or they can build from scratch

Explore different options and test with users to deliver the best user experience (ie: how user would use the app template to quickly generate predictions).

Axon

Senior Product Designer

June 2021 - December 2022 (1 year 7 months)

Take charge of designing new features for Axon Standards, a SaaS product to help police agencies with the documentation and processes for Internal Affairs. Primary focus is to build an Early Intervention System to help supervisors detect officers who seem to be having performance problems and provide them with the appropriate next actions according to their own policy.

Zalo

UI/UX Lead

September 2017 - January 2021 (3 years 5 months)

Work with product managers to design new features, build mobile prototypes for advanced interaction and create task lists for usability testing.

Take responsibility in new Zalo UI to create a modern look that appeals more to younger users.

Define current design inconsistency issues, rebuild design systems and break into modular components for better management and syncing across the team

GEEK Up

Product Design Lead

October 2015 - September 2017 (2 years)

Undertake projects from local and international startups that are in need of UX-emphasis creative solution for their MVP in different industries (HR, Real estate, Food, Hospitality...)

Provide UX consultation on different projects, from web development to mobile apps and brand campaigns and work with the development team to implement design and perform user testing to make sure all scenarios/flows are well covered.

Supervise other designers so that everyone follows the design thinking process and knows how to ask the right questions before jumping into creating solutions.

Please visit https://geekup.vn/ for more

Personal

Freelance UI/UX and graphic designer March 2013 - December 2015 (2 years 10 months) vietnam

- Create branding identity for local companies (Mr.Potato, Myvi, BP Gem, La lumiere bar, Hoang Ong seafood...)

- Customize, design and fine tune web and app interfaces for foreign clients (Singapore and Europe)

ALLDAY

UI/UX Designer

January 2015 - October 2015 (10 months)

Responsible for the website refresh (UX flow/ look & feel).

Prototyping how the website works for responsive layout

Developing a new web app platform for social media management, data analytics and content sharing.

Hoiio

UI / UX Designer

September 2013 - November 2014 (1 year 3 months)

- Brainstorm and develop wireframes, lo-fi to hi-fi mockups and make numerous iterations for telecommunication apps (SMS marketing, Phone, Fax, Contacts....).
- In charge of defining UI patterns and make sure all apps follow the style guide.
- Support responsive layout based on Bootstrap framework.

TBWA

Graphic designer (Young Blood) October 2012 - February 2013 (5 months)

- Multitask different design project for different accounts in TBWA Vietnam, mainly POSM (Mobifone, SCB, PhanerPie, LaRue beer...)
- Create various options for each brief, make changes based on client's feedback and finalize the artwork and apply to different platforms.
- Work as a team to pitch ideas and deliver the best solutions for each brief.

Draftfcb

Intern as Graphic designer
June 2012 - September 2012 (4 months)

DraftFCB Vietnam

- Photo manipulate in DraftFCB for adverting campaigns : Kido icecream Winner ad, Three Lady cooks tvc, Redbul billboard design
- Work on the creative brief, under the art director's guidance to make different artwork and options to propose to the clients.
- Produce sketches and final layouts to deliver the message with greatest impact while still keeping legibility

Education

RMIT University

Bachelor of Multimedia Design, Graphic Design · (2009 - 2013)

Le Hong Phong High School

High School · (2007 - 2009)